MARIA MIRELES

AUSTIN, TEXAS 78744

T: (512) 296-9696

E: mireles335@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maria-erika-mireles-7b7b27210/

Github: https://github.com/mariamv29

Portfolio: https://mariamv29.github.io/professional-portfolio/

Technical Skills:

Experience level: since April 2021

- Frontend: HTML5, CSS, Advanced CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Web-API, Regex.
- Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, Webpack.

Soft Skills:

- Management, leadership, customer service, communicator, active listening, mentoring, collaborative, conflict resolution, innovative, adaptable, time management, bilingual.

Projects:

Role in project: JavaScript. Web-API functioning.

- Healthy Habits
 - Healthy Craves allows users to search and save meals and find a healthy version they can follow from a recipe. This helps individuals stay on track by taking their favorite foods and showing them a healthy alternative.
 - My responsibility and role in Healthy Craves was to create one of the two Web-API
 JavaScript functionality and also helped with the project's CSS.
 - o GitHub: https://github.com/mariamv29/healthy-craves.git
 - o Deployed link: https://mariamv29.github.io/healthy-craves/
- Libro-Fy

Role in project: Set up DB, MySQL.

- Libro-fy is website that allows their users to automatically get books based on recommendations, shares, likes and common interests. By simply creating an account the user will be able to save and rank their favorite books in order to create a personal virtual bookshelf
- My responsibility on Libro-Fy was to set up the database using MySQL and setting up the routes. As well, as to deploy the application using Heroku.
- o GitHub: https://github.com/mariamv29/libro-fy
- Deployed link: https://libro-fy.herokuapp.com/

Skills:

 Fluent in both English and Spanish, 60 GWAM, customer service experience, active listening, superior leadership and communication experience, proficient in computer navigational skills, ability to adapt to any environment, multitasking and time management, work independently, and claims adjuster license holder.

Work Experience:

Progressive ins Co. Austin, TX Sept 2018- present.

Claim Loss Reporting Unit - Bilingual Spanish Representative

- Answer incoming calls from customers looking to report a new claim.
- As a CLRU representative my main objective is to provide the customer with a smooth and simple claim filing process.
- Make sure to target and fulfill customer needs to the best of my ability by identifying the current damage to vehicles and make fast and appropriate decisions based on the status of the customers' needs. For example: scheduling car rental reservations, inspections, repairs, and providing tow assistance.
- Educate customers if unfamiliar with the report claim process.
- Helping my team members with any questions or concerns. For example, learning from side-by-side observations and collaborations.
- Strive to execute the 5 objectives every day when coming into work.

Team Based Handling - Claim Representative, since July 7, 2019 – present.

- As a team-based handling representative, my main objective is to handle animal and noncomplex weather claims by completing the claim investigation process to assure coverage is in line with customer's policy.
- Maintain a transparent customer handling process through a well-documented transcript of each claim received.
- Take incoming calls as well as making outbound calls to customers to make initial contact and provide additional contact if needed to resolve the claim.
- It is my responsibility to schedule and make any payments that need to be issued under the claim.
- When handling claims, it is my duty to stay available and help the customer when involved in accident/ incident.
- My job role also includes resolving problems that might arise when the claim in still in process. For example, from being in contact with everyone involved in the claim, from rental facilities to collision centers, while making sure there is no miscommunication that might affect the claim.
- As a claims Adjuster, the ability to multi-task, handle large workloads and staying organized is my main priority when logging into work.
- In my department I am also part of the mentor on-boarding program for newly hired representatives.

Afterschool Centers on Education (ACE) with Austin Independent School District Austin, TX 2015-Sept 2018.

Program Assistant/ Program Instructor

- Began as a program instructor, taking charge of the craft club and a Pre-k group. The members of the craft club were 2nd, 3rd, and 5th graders.
- As the Pre-K instructor I made sure the kids ate their snack, took care of them during playtime and planned fun/ easy activities.
- Helped students from Kinder- 5th grade with their homework.
- After a few months working with ACE I got promoted to Program Assistant. I'm in charge of
 imputing all the daily students' attendance into the system, making informational flyers for
 parents. I also prepare daily binders for the program's instructors with attendance rosters
 and class instructions.
- Currently taking care of any behavior or conduct troubles, accidents, and bullying issues the students may experience while in class.
- I Make sure all program technology and materials are returned at the end of the program.
- Call parents with any necessary information and answer parent's questions and concerns regarding the program's processes', plans, and student expectations.

In charge of the afterschool program when the program's director is out.

Cricket Wireless Austin, TX 2013-2014

Sales Associate

- -Persuaded and encouraged customers to buy store's product.
- -Helped customers with any questions and concerns, also ensured they had an enjoyable time at the store.
- -Answered any incoming calls and maintained my work area clean. Was hold accountable for all merchandise and cash at the end of my shift.
- -Served as the store's cashier, activated over 30 phones a day and processed around 90 mobile payments a day.

Education:

William B. Travis High School

Austin, TX June 2015

- Graduated high school June 4, 2015, and was part of school related organizations
- College:
- The University of Texas at Austin Certificate

Austin, TX October 2021

- I am currently attending a Coding Boot Camp program with UT Austin with the goal to obtain a full-stack Web Developer certification.
- Austin Community College

Austin, TX 2017

 Attended Austin Community College, I finished my third semester of college in December 2017. Once I accumulate enough transferable credits, I plan to transfer to a 4-year college and obtain a bachelors' degree in Business Administration.